# Hadi Lashkari Ghouchani

### Software Engineer

@ me@hadilg.com

hadilg.com

O Toronto, Canada

github.com/hadilq

@hadilq@androiddev.social

in linkedin.com/in/hadilq

#### **Summary**

A curious developer with over 17 years of experience in software development, where almost 7 years of his experience covers Android development, over 2 years covers teaching algorithms and programming in universities, and over 8 years covers academic and self-employed experiences while he was a student.

An Introvert person who has profound learning and contributing skills. A creative, value driven and passionate developer who enjoys doing math, solving problems and creating scalable, maintainable, testable and efficient apps to make the world a better place to live.

A person whose goal is to surround himself with creative, clever, motivative and happy persons, so he can

continuously learn more and more. He's interested in decreasing build time, improving productivity of engineers by tooling. He's most productive

when he has the ownership of his work in an environment without hierarchy.

### **Experience**

#### Software Engineer

at MobileLIVE 🛗 Apr. 2021 - Present O Toronto, Canada

MobileLIVE is a Canadian tech-service provider unifying people, technology, and business to accelerate digital transformation. Over this time, he worked in Bell Canada as a full-time contractor. Bell Canada is subsidiary Bell Aliant provides services in the Atlantic provinces. It provides mobile service through its Bell Mobility (including Virgin Mobile Canada) subsidiary, and television through its Bell Satellite TV and Bell Fibe TV subsidiaries.

#### Mission:

- Introduced RFCs to make technical decisions and steps to applying on any new idea.
- Adding value by teaching and discussing SOLID principles, and best practices of modularization, feature flags, and monorepo, etc
- Raise and implement the idea of automatically cloning and building all the source code in the multi-repo setup to reduce version conflicts, and improve code visibility for debugging purposes
- Raise the need for Gradle Enterprise and Productivity Engineer in the team, which leads to be the one who setup the Gradle Enterprise in the project to improve the build time, and create the necessary tools.
- Investigate problems related to proxy and self-signed certificates in VPN networks, where by implementing a script to install them automatically increased the build count in GE dashboard by 164%
- Implement a Jetpack Compose desktop app, to prepare the configuration for building Bell's project.
- Raise and implement the need for Gradle Converntional Plugins to reduce duplication and errors, and also improve consistency among Gradle configurations and versions of external libraries.

#### Technologies

- Kotlin Coroutines / Mockk, Mockito, jUnit, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Lane based branching strategy, CI/CD
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Gitlab, Jenkins, Slack, Branch.io, inVision, Dynatrace, etc.

### Staff Android Developer

m Oct. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Barcelona, Spain

iFood is an ambitious project to build an entire food delivery ecosystem for all around the world. Currently, it's the biggest food delivery in Brazil, Colombia and Mexico, with 50+ million apps installed on Android devices alone. The Android project is highly modularized to make it possible for 50+ developers working on it fast.

#### Mission:

- · Propose and implement composite build to handle dependency management in Gradle. It decreased the rebuild time while updating a library from more than 13 min to less than a minute
- Implement Android side of metadata project. Its purpose is gathering all information of our highly modularized Android/iOS projects in a dashboard along backend information
- Propose and apply a concept to move out the legacy code from the root module. It decreased the rebuild time of freed up modules by 55%
- Wrap up external libraries to better handling panic situations.

### Technologies:

- Dagger 2, Room, Kotlin Coroutines, Moshi, WorkManager / Mockk, Robolectric, jUnit, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD, Gradle Enterprise
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Databricks, Firebase, Bugsnag, Logzio, etc.

### Senior Android Developer

at Letgo

m Oct. 2019 - Mar. 2021

Barcelona, Spain

Letgo is the biggest classified marketplace in Turkey with 15+ million apps installed on Android devices

### Mission:

- Improve the performance of loading feeds by at least a minute
- · Fix multiple Memory leaks
- Known as "The man who broke the escape room" to emphasize his ability to think out of the box
- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Room / Mockito, Espresso, Robolectric, Jacoco, Ktlint, Fastlane, etc. Agile. Sprint. Github Flow, CI/CD, Dynamic Feature Module Delivery
  - Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Figma, New Relic, Firebase, Amplitude, etc.

### Lead Android Developer

at Sheypoor

🛗 Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor is one of two lead classified marketplaces in Iran with 1.5+ million users per day, 13+ million overall users and 344+ million sessions.

Increase the number of users per day from 0.5+ million to 1.5+ million in a year.

### Technologies:

- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Butter Knife, Greendao / Mockito, Espresso, Jacoco, etc.
- Agile, Kanban, Git Flow, CI/CD / Pivotal Tracker, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Zeplin, etc.

### Senior Android Developer

at Myket

Tehran, Iran

Myket is one of two lead app stores in Iran with over 8+ million users. TL;DR Mission: Starting TDD and installing Jenking's pipeline to handle CI/CD.

## Java and C# developer

at Soha System

mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

O Tehran, Iran

SOHA is formed to focus on solutions based on smart cards. TL:DR Mission: Implementing Android and

### **Article / Repository**

M 2023 Post: Dependency Inversion Principle

📆 2023 Contributing to nixpkgs/androidenv: Nix is a language that is designed to have reproducibile output.

2022 Sample App: Molecule sample app to solve some scoping problems in Android development.

2022 Sample App: Molecule sample app to solve some scoping problems in Android developme
 2022 Post: Reproducibility
 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Are feature flags, build variants, and sample apps related concepts?

📆 2021 iFood Engneering post: Modularization tip: optimize the Root Module. 🐧 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Happy Railway. An improvement for Railway Oriented Programming in Kotlin. 2021 Library: Happy is a library to auto-generate Kotlin code to make calling APIs more concise

↑ 2020 POC: Rust Flutter Reactive is an idea to use Flutter as UI and Rust for the main project. ↑ 2020 Make Log4k Multiplatform: Simple logging library for Android, iOS, Mac, etc.

M 2020 ProAndroidDev post: A/B Testing Myths

→ 2020 Sample App: Provide a full implementation for a No-Framework Dependency Injection in Kotlin

 $\bigcirc$  2020 Contributing on  $\Lambda$ rrow Library:  $\Lambda$ rrow is a library for Typed Functional Programming in Kotlin

O 2020 Library: A Kotlin compiler plugin that generates trackable method
2020 Medium post: Save State By Using RxJava or Kotlin Flow 2020 Medium post: RxJava instead of LiveData in MVVM

2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and upstreams in RxJava 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and Kotlin Coroutines

2020 Library: Simplifier for unnecessary complex lifecycles

 2019 Sample App: Functional Programming + Clean Architecture
 2019 Sample App: Movie Challenge
 2019 Math Library: Modularized, mathematical and multiplatform Kotlin library ☑ 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Logging in Kotlin • 2018 Log4k Library: Easy logging library, but unfortunately it's in Sheypoor repository

M 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Reactive MVVM architectural pattern

↑ 2018 Sample App: Clean Architecture + RMVVM
↑ 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Loading entities from database and server API by using RxJava
↑ 2018 ProAndroidDev post: LiveData with single events

🔾 2018 LiveEvent library: It's useful to propagate single event to View

### **Education**

Sharif University Of Technology Payame Noor University

M.Sc B.Sc

in Physics in Physics

∰ Feb. 2010 m Jul. 2007

O Tehran, Iran Mashhad, Iran

### **Tools / Skills**

#### Android

Partially Open Source Mobile Lifecycles/LiveData/Navigation/Paging/ViewModel Multidex/Test/Data Binding/WorkManager/Room Android Architecture Components/JetPack Anvil/Dagger 2/RxJava 2/Retrofit 2/.. Kotlin Multiplatform/Kotlin Coroutines Kotlin Compiler Plugin/KSP/. Compose/Data Binding/View Binding/...

Summary of why you're interested: It's partially open source OS. Generally interested on Mobile Technologies.

#### Flutter

StatelessWidget/StatefulWidget StreamController/Isolates

Summary of why you're interested: Generally interested on all cross-platform and multi-platform solutions.

#### Rust

tonic/prost/openssl/tokio/flatbuffers/thrift Rc/Arc/Mutex

Summary of why you're interested: Rust's type system is what you need for scale-up. Borrow Checker restrictly stops any memory leaks. Bevy, and Dioxus frameworks look like good candidates for cross-platform solutions.

#### Nix

NixOS/Nix Darwin mkDrivation/mkShell

Summary of why you're interested: Reproducibility is the key to productivity.

#### Architecture

Clean Architecture/Hexagonal Architecture Unidirectional data flow Architecture MVVM/MVI/MVP/RMVVM

#### Principle

Clean Code/SOLID **Object Oriented Programming** Functional Programming Stable Dependencies Principle Stable Abstractions Principle

#### Design Pattern Factory/Builder/Singleton/...

Adapter/Facade/Proxy/Visitor/Delegate/... Strategy/Chain of responsibility/...

#### Android test library JUnit/Mockito/Espresso/Jacoco/...

**Build Tool** Gradle/Cargo/Sbt/Maven/Ant/Make/...

### **Command Line Tool** grep/sed/netstat/awk/docker/..

adb/sdkmanager/avdmanager/..

### **Development Tool** Pivotal Tracker/Jira/Jenkins/Travis/CircleCi/...

Programing Language Java/Kotlin/Rust/Scala/Haskell/Python Groovy/Dart/Javascript/Ruby...

### Operating System

Linux(Nix OS/Fedora/Ubuntu/Debian), OS X

### Special Honor

- 2020 Had an offer from MobileLIVE, Toronto, Canada
- 2020 Had an offer from iFood, Remote - 2019 Had an offer from Kik, Kitechener, Canada
- 2019 Had an offer from Letgo, Barcelona, Spain 2019 Had an offer from CRITICAL Techworks, BMW, Porto, Portugal
- 2019 Had an offer from The Next Big Thing, Berlin, Germany
- 2018 Received result-oriented badge in Sheypoor 2007 Ranked 44th among more than five thousand participants in the National Graduate Entrance Exam in

### Language

English: Advance Farsi: Native

The source of this resume is in github Built on August 28, 2023